

Calgary, Alberta, Canada 403-973-6874

julesrubies@gmail.com

Website: jrmuri.dev

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jr-muri-ui GitHub: qithub.com/JulesRuby

PROFILE

Full-stack web developer with a strong focus on UI. Coming from 5 years of customer service roles, 3 years as a professional photographer, and over the past 3 years studying the field of web development. Possessing a strong overlap of interpersonal, creative, and technical skills to leverage in favor of modern tech environments.

SKILLS

Languages: HTML5 // CSS3 // JavaScript Database: MongoDB

Frameworks: Vue Concepts: Responsive Design // REST API

Tools: Adobe CC // Figma // VS Code // Git

EDUCATION

Web Developer Certification (With Honors GPA: 3.84) — SAIT Polytechnic January 2020 — July 2020

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Web Development Certification — Mount Royal University

January 2018 — May 2018

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Chemical Laboratory Technologies Diploma — SAIT Polytechnic

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

September 2007 – June 2010

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Calefy - Student Developer

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

May 2020 - July 2020

- Developed stateful locking slider component, functionally allowing users to indicate allocation of investments
- Leveraged React, and Material UI in the development of custom, reusable form input components, expanding the scope of options in the dynamic form builder application
- Engaged in live component usability testing and evaluation from marketing team

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jules Ruby Photography - Event Photographer

August 2016 – Present

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Kinjo Sushi & Grill — Supervisor/Server/'Pockyman'

August 2015 — January 2020

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Shell - Chemical Technologist

August 2010 - September 2014

Calgary, Alberta, Canada

PROJECTS

"Reely" Movie Nominations

Technologies: Vue, Vuex, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Netlify, Git

Summary: Stateful web app that consumes omdbAPI endpoints to fetch movie data. The user manages a list of

nominations from Vuex and "submits" them when the limit is reached.

Live: https://sad-morse-2b9e87.netlify.app

Repo: https://github.com/JulesRuby/turgid-watermelon

Personal Portfolio Website

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Netlify, Git, SVG

Summary: Design and create a personal website to showcase some of my projects and portfolio. As well as have some fun experimenting with CSS3 to infuse it with modern retro/synthwave appearance. Implemented client-side form

validation via JavaScript. **Live**: https://jrmuri.dev/

Repo: https://github.com/JulesRuby/jr-muri-website-simple

Business Website Sky Electric

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Netlify, Git

Summary: Developed a business website for an electrical contracting business, using responsive design practices.

Live: https://www.skyelectric.ca/

Repo: https://github.com/JulesRuby/skyelectric

Jekyll Music Blog Mockup

Technologies: Ruby, Jekyll, Liquid, HTML5, CSS3, Netlify, Git

Summary: Create a mockup of a music blog format, utilizing Jekyll Kramdown, and Liquid markdown syntax to

template out the elements.

Live: https://jekyll-music-blog-mock.netlify.app

Repo: https://github.com/JulesRuby/jekyll-assignment

Custom Gallery Website

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, EJS, MongoDB, Heroku, Git

Summary: Develop and deploy a static website using EJS to template it, so that it can easily generate new content as it is added to the database. This web site's primary feature is the custom image gallery, which showcases the power of the templating engine to draw from stored data.

Live: https://mongoose-ejs-gallery.herokuapp.com/

Repo: https://github.com/JulesRuby/mongoosee-ejs-gallery